Woodcock, Alfred H.; Papers ua902.028
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Alfred H. Woodcock Papers
1930-1995
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Woodcock, Alfred H.
ua902.028
7.25 cubic ft.
Atmospheric researcher and oceanographer from Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (WHOI) and the University of Hawaii, Woodcock collaborated with Duncan Blanchard and the U.S. Navy on research such as Project Shower, atmospheric sea salt and volcanic mountain breathing.
Biographical Sketch
Alfred H. Woodcock was born on September 7, 1905 in Atlanta, Georgia. His formal education ended very early as his father had very little regard for school and Woodcock went to work in a wide variety of jobs in the seasonal economy of the southeastern United States after dropping out of high school. After moving to Massachusetts and resuming his education at a local agricultural school, he worked on farms and did odd jobs. Woodcock heard the research vessel Atlantis was looking for hands to sign on for a research cruise under the command of Columbus Iselin. The Atlantis was the first deep-water research ship of the fledgling Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (WHOI). Under the direction of Dr. Henry Bigelow of Harvard University, WHOI was formed in 1930 and funded by a Rockefeller Foundation grant of 3 million dollars. Woodcock signed on and became a valued member of the crew, rising to the position of chief scientist in 1935. Woodcock had found his calling in atmospheric research and oceanography, and he began his research into the soaring patterns of marine birds, sailing patterns of jellyfish and the ways that dolphins and porpoises ride along the bow of sailing ships. Woodcock continued to conduct experiments aboard the Atlantis until 1942.
During the Second World War, Woodcock worked with the U.S. Navy to develop smoke screens that could be used to camouflage allied vessels at sea. After the end of the war, Woodcock continued to work in conjunction with the Navy to study wind patterns at sea. Beginning in 1942 he was employed at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute in Massachusetts, first as a research associate and then as an oceanographer. He conducted research into oceanography and atmospheric science, studying sea salt and its affect on precipitation. From 1949 to 1953 Woodcock published a series of groundbreaking scientific papers about the research he had conducted into atmospheric sea salt. In 1951, he met and began to work with one of his primary collaborators, Duncan Blanchard. Woodcock and Blanchard would collaborate on atmospheric research and carry on a long running correspondence.
In the early 1950s Woodcock was involved in Project Shower, which investigated the physics and chemistry of warm rain in Hawaii. This was a cooperative project involving WHOI and the Pineapple Research Institute and funded by the Office of Naval Research (ONR). The data and final report of Project Shower was published in 1957 in the journal Tellus. Woodcock also published a paper in 1958 which dealt with the behavior of atmospheric sea salt in hurricanes. In this period Woodcock collaborated with Duncan Blanchard and also with chemist James Lodge and meteorologist E.G. "Taffy" Bowen among others. In 1961 Woodcock was awarded an honorary PhD from Long Island University as a doctor of science. It was not long after (1962) that Dr. Woodcock moved to Hawaii, where he concentrated on the study of atmospheric sea salt in Hawaii from 1962 to 1965.
From 1963 to 1972 Woodcock was a research associate in the Department of Oceanography at the University of Hawaii and a research associate at the Hawaiian Institute of Geophysics. In Hawaii, Woodcock conducted atmospheric studies at the dormant volcano Mauna Kea and also did research on Lake Waiau, an alpine lake that is near the summit of Mauna Kea. He developed a theory of "mountain breathing" where gasses entered and exited the mountain. Woodcock conducted research into the movement patterns of the Portuguese Man 'o War, Physalia, and continued research into Sargassum and studies of Hawaiian cloud physics. His primary collaborator during this period continued to be Duncan Blanchard, but he also conducted research with James Hughes of ONR, as well as researchers Jack Warner and Sean Twomey in Australia.
Woodcock was retired from the University of Hawaii in 1972, but continued to work on projects relating to atmospheric science. Woodcock became interested in fog formation and conducted research into fog in Alaska and Woods Hole, MA. He continued the research begun in the 1960s by further investigating the phenomenon of mountain breathing at Mauna Kea and did further research in Lake Waiau. Much of the funding for Woodcock's research came from the Office of Naval Research and his primary contact was James Hughes, in the Atmospheric Research department of the Office of Naval Research. Woodcock's ONR funding began with Project Shower and was terminated in 1984. In 1988, Woodcock was named Scientist Emeritus by the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute and in 1994 he was presented with a lifetime achievement award by the American Meteorological Society.
Chronology of Events
1905 September 7 Born in Atlanta, GA
1931 Joins the research vessel Atlantis, under the command of Columbus Iselin
1931 1942 Technician, Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute
1935 Sole scientist on the Atlantis' North Atlantic voyage
1938 Publishes a paper in The Atlantic Monthly on the flight patterns of birds
1940 Publishes a paper on soaring gulls in The Journal of Marine Research
1941 Chief scientist aboard the Atlantis
1941 Smoke screen project begins in conjunction with the U.S. Navy
1942 1946 Research Associate, Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute
1944 Begins research into Physalia/Portuguese Man o' War
1946 1963 Oceanographer, Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute
1947 Wyman/Woodcock report released on the temperature lapse rate in clouds
1947 1949 Woodcock studies the seaweed genus Sargassum
1949 Begins research into atmospheric sea salt
1949 1953 Publishes a series of groundbreaking papers on atmospheric sea salt.
1951 Begins working with Duncan Blanchard at Woods Hole
1954 Project Shower begins (study of the physics and chemistry of warm rain)
1957 Publishes results of Project Shower in Tellus
1958 Publishes a paper about the behavior of atmospheric sea salt in hurricanes
1961 Awarded honorary PhD from Long Island University
1962 Moves to Hawaii
1962 1965 Peak of Woodcock's research into atmospheric sea salt
1963 1972 Research affiliate, Dept. of Oceanography, University of Hawaii
1963 1972 Research associate, Hawaiian Institute of Geophysics
1974 (ca.) Conducts research into fog formation in Alaska and Woods Hole
1975 Revisits gull research
1988 Emeritus Scientist, Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute
1994 Receives American Meteorological Society's Lifetime Achievement Award
Scope and Contents
The material in this collection documents the correspondence and scientific research of Alfred H. Woodcock. Correspondence files date from 1930-1995 and consist of correspondence from the scientists that Woodcock worked and collaborated with, along with carbons of his original correspondence, as well as journal articles and a small amount of personal correspondence. Most of the correspondence is related to science and the topics that Woodcock was investigating. There is very little correspondence for the years 1930-1950. Woodcock's major collaborators were atmospheric scientist Duncan Blanchard, U.S. Navy scientist James Hughes, chemist James Lodge, and atmospheric researcher Sean Twomey. The scientific research files date from 1937-1986 and consist of original data collected by Woodcock as well as journal articles, record books, and photographs. Information about the scientists Woodcock collaborated with can be found in the correspondence files. Information about the scientific projects that Woodcock researched can be found in the scientific research files. Major projects and research covered by the collection includes the study of the soaring patterns of marine birds, 1931-1942, 1975; Woodcock's study of atmospheric sea salt, 1950-1965; Project Shower, a major study of warm rain in Hawaii, 1954-1957; the study of the alpine environment on the volcano Mauna Kea and Lake Waiau, 1956-1975. Also covered are Woodcock's study of the seaweed Sargassum, 1944-1949; and the Portuguese man 'o war Physalia, 1944-1970. Research pertaining to Woodcock's fog studies dates from 1977-1981. Note that in some files the topic can cover many years with significant gaps, and that occasionally multiple topics are covered within one folder. The dates of research are those in which the primary research was conducted; other material in the files such as journal articles and background material may predate the primary research.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Alfred H. Woodcock in October, 1999.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Conservation and the Environment; Atmosphere -- Research -- Hawaii.; Atmosphere -- Research -- Massachusetts.; Cloud physics.; Ecology -- Research -- Hawaii.; Fog -- Research -- Massachusetts.; Geography -- Research -- Hawaii.; Geography -- Research -- Massachusetts.; Geology -- Research -- Hawaii.; Geology -- Research -- Massachusetts.; Oceanographic research ships -- Massachusetts.; Oceanography -- Research -- Hawaii.; Oceanography -- Research -- Massachusetts.; Precipitation (Meteorology) -- Measurement..; Smoke screens.; Volcanoes -- Hawaii.; Weather.; UAlbany Faculty & Alumni Papers; Woodcock, Alfred H.; Bigelow, Henry B. (Henry Bryant), 1879-; Blanchard, Duncan C. (Duncan Cromwell), 1924-; Bowen, E. G.; Duce, Robert A., 1935-; Eriksson, Erik, 1917-; Faller, Alan J.; Friedman, Irving, 1920-2005.; Hughes, James A.; Iselin, Columbus O’Donnell, 1904-; Knight, Charles A. (Charles Alfred), 1936-; Lodge, James P.; Iselin, Columbus O’Donnell, 1904-; Renn, Charles E. (Charles Easterday), 1905-; Schaefer, Vincent J.; Twomey, Sean A. (Sean Andrew), 1928-; American Meteorological Society.; State University of New York. Atmospheric Sciences Research Center.; C.S.I.R.O. Radiophysics Laboratory.; Hawaii Institute of Geophysics.; International Meteorological Institute in Stockholm.; Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Department of Geology and Geophysics.; United States. Department of Defense.; National Science Foundation (U.S.); University of Hawaii (System). School of Ocean and Earth Science and Technology.; Colorado. Office of State Geologist.; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.); Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution.
- Correspondence, 1930-1995; 1; 3.0 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  Types of material include letters, carbon copies, journal articles, photographs and scientific research. Correspondence arranged chronologically pertaining to Woodcock's work aboard the research vessel Atlantis, 1930-1939, and work with the Navy on the smoke screens at sea project, 1944-45. Research into atmospheric sea salts and sea salt nuclei 1947-1986; Project Shower research into warm rain in Hawaii, 1954-1957; and Hawaiian cloud physics, 1952-1965. Also included is correspondence pertaining to Woodcock's study of Hawaiian rainfall, 1967-1972; atmospheric studies at the volcano Mauna Kea, 1965-1977; permafrost at Mauna Kea, 1969-1977; "mountain breathing" at Mauna Kea, 1976-1979; and Lake Waiau, 1965-1985. Correspondence dealing with Woodcock's research into sea salt, and studies of canal fog, 1979-1986. Other topics of correspondence include: physalia, 1944-1970; soaring gulls, 1937-1938; wave riding dolphins, 1946-1953; sargassum, 1947-1949; bursting bubbles, 1976; hail, 1976; Woodcock's research into his CIA file, 1977; hurricanes, 1985; slush and ice on lakes and ponds, 1987; rain droplet formation in clouds, 1990, study of Hawaiian trade winds, 1991; Woodcock's reception of the American Meteorological Society's lifetime achievement award, 1994; and budgetary matters. Correspondents include Columbus Iselin, director of the Atlantis research project, 1930-39, atmospheric scientist and meteorologist Duncan Blanchard, 1955-1995; U.S. Navy atmospheric scientist James Hughes, 1955-1984; chemist James Lodge, 1955-1965; meteorologist and atmospheric scientist E.G. "Taffy" Bowen 1955-1965; and atmospheric researcher Erik Erikkson, 1955-1965; oceanographer Robert Duce 1965-1977; researchers Jack Warner and Sean Twomey, 1969-1977; Charles Penn, 1981-1985; Irving Friedman, 1977-1979; Charles Knight, 1989-1991; as well as Vincent Schaefer, Allen Faller and Irving Friedman. See the box and folder list for a detailed description of the contents of the containers.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1930-1939 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Project Shower Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    (Correspondence relating to Project Shower, the study of warm rain in Hawaii).
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Project Shower correspondence, 1953 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 18-19)
  - Project Shower correspondence, 1954 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 20-22)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 23-24)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 29-30)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 32-33)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 35-36)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 4-5)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 9-10)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 11-12)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 13-14)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 15-16)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 17-18)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 19-20)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 21-22)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 9-10)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with James Hughes, 1964-1984 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 23)
- Scientific Research, 1937-1986; 2; 4.25 cubic ft.
  This series collects journal articles, correspondence, data, record books, photographs, notes, monographs, diagrams and tables. Alfred H. Woodcock's research into a variety of topics including Lake Waiau, 1965-1970, 1978, 1982; salt spray in hurricanes, 1956-1958, 1962-1968, 1974; mountain breathing, 1974-1978; sea salt, 1959-1966; soaring flight data, 1937-1938, 1945, 1952, 1966; porpoise and wave riding dolphins, 1940, 1946-1953, 1960; glacier studies, 1960, 1962, 1969-1976, 1979; ice melt patterns, 1961, 1981-1982; ice melt data, 1946-1950, 1959, 1962, 1965; fog studies, 1981; Mauna Kea/Lake Waiau studies, 1965-1975; telescope studies, 1974, 1982; atmospheric research, 1946-1956, 1971-1982; deuterium, 1951, 1961-1963; sargassum, 1947-1949; physalia, 1944-1970; volcano steam cloud, 1960; smoke screen at sea, 1944-1946; declassified, 1973. See the box and folder list for a detailed description of the contents of the containers.
  - Soaring data - convective, 1937-1938 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 1)
  - Soaring data - dynamic, 1937-1938 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 2)
  - Porpoise bow and wave riding 1940, 1948-1953; 1960 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 3)
  - A theory of surface water deduced, etc, 1941-1963 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 4)
  - A holy smoke, 1944 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 5)
  - A smoke, 1944-1945 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 6)
  - Final report on the behavior of smoke screens at sea, 1944-1945 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 7-8)
  - Tests on the behavior of smoke screens at sea, 1944-1945 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 9)
  - Tests on the behavior of smoke screens at sea, 1944-1945 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 10-11)
  - Physalia, 1944-1963; 2.10 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 12)
    - a. Notebook, "Spring 1961 P-p trip data and rough log of P-p experiments in Florida"
    - b. a graph of observations of Physalia in the Florida Straits, 1961 March
    - c. a reprint with some penciled notes of Woodcock's publication, "Dimorphism in the Portuguese Man-Of-War", Nature, Vol 178, 253-255, 1956 August 4
    - d. a reprint of Everet C. Jones, "Tremoctopus violaceus Uses Physalia Tentacles as Weapons, Science, Vol 139, No 3556, 764-66, 1963 February 22
    - e. P-p dipping and sailing abs. notes, 1963 July; 3 pages
    - f. 5 three x five cards with citations and brief notes on articles
    - g., 2 pages of notes
      One page on ships reports, 1882-1903, one page labeled Pensacola-Santa Rosa, observations, on float lengths.
    - h. a chart titled Fig 47 "Idealized Drawings of Wind-Induced Helical Motions in surface waters, with an illustration of the possible effects of asymmetrical vortices upon the drift of bottles and of physalia
    - i. reprint of Woodcock, "A theory of surface water motion deduced from the wind-induced motion of the Physalia"Sears Foundation: Journal of Marine Research, Vol. 5, No. 3, pp. 196-205, 1944 October 20
    - j. Map of Trinidad and Tobago
  - Log book no.4 WHOL, 1945-1950 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 13)
  - Hawaiian Data, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 14)
  - Note on physalia symmetry, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 15)
  - Vertical motion exchange of heat and water between the air and sea, 1946; 2 folders (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 16-17)
  - The preparation and use of water sensitive coatings for sampling cloud particles, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 18)
  - Grass pond area, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 19)
  - Marine studio experiment on porpoise density, 1946; 1948-1950 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 20)
  - Sargassum pressure tests Bermuda bio. station St. Georges, Bermuda, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 21)
  - Sargassum studies, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 22)
  - Subsurface sargassum, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 23)
  - Sargassum notebook, 1948 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 24)
  - Salt spray data, 1948 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 25)
  - Sea and lake boundary, layer conditions, bubbles and foaming, 1948; 1950; 1952; 1960 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 26)
  - Wave riding dolphins, 1948-1949 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 27)
  - The swimming of dolphins, 1948-1950; 1960 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 28)
  - Subsurface sargassum manuscript, 1949 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 29)
  - Melting patterns in shallow ponds, 1949-1950 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 30)
  - Grass Pond-Long Island, 1949; 1962 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 31)
  - Data book impact sampling 1950, Nassau trip 1960, Woods Hole, MA, USA, 1950 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 32)
  - Original data June 1951, Ohan, TH (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 33)
  - December 1951-Summer 1954 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 34)
  - Hawaii, 1952 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 35)
  - Cloud paper tables, 1953 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 36)
  - Salt induced convection and clouds "bits and pieces", 1953; 1956 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 37)
  - Bubbles from melting snow, 1953; 1957; 1971; 1974 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 38)
  - Project shower, Kilauea "Kapoho" eruption 1954, 1960 (Box 4 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 39)
  - Contribution to the study of the origin of nitrogen in atmospheric precipitation, 1955 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 1)
  - Atmospheric salt sampling, 1955-1956 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 2)
  - Flight and field data, 1955; 1961; 1963-1965 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 3)
  - Ideas for further physalia studies, 1956; 2.40 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 4)
    - a. One page titled: "Tentative suggestions for Physalia studies, emphasizing their sailing habits", 1956 August 5
      an outline in pencil.
    - b. Seven pages ripped out of a small notebook with observations, 03/24/1946; 03/26/1946; 03/31/1946; 04/06/1946
  - Dimorphism in the Portuguese Man-of-War, 1956; 2.41 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 5)
    - a. Article "Dimorphism in the Portuguese Man-of-War", 1956 March 28
      Typescript inscribed 2nd corrected copy, of 7 pages including bib & notes, & three pages of graphs accompanying the article & two tables (one draft, on final) of observations of right and left handed Physalia seen on the surface of the open sea.
    - b. Correspondence with MacMillan & Co.
      re the submission, two pages, two post cards dated March 1956.
    - c. A second set of the three figures which appear the same but are not numbered
    - d. Three pages of penciled drafts of figure 1 & 2, and of table 1
  - Salt spray in hurricanes, 1956-1958; 1974 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 6)
  - Factors affecting the distribution of villia - Dr. G.O. Mackie, ca. 1957 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 7)
  - Physalia data, 1957-1958 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 8)